嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey
摩妮卡
Monica?
现在几点了
What time is it?
9点
Uh, 9.
可是外面还很黑
But it's dark out.
那是因为你老是睡到中午  傻瓜
Um, well, that's because you always sleep till noon, silly.
9点就是这么黑
This is what 9 looks like.
那我该梳洗一下
I guess I'll get washed up then.
准备看日出
Watch that sunrise.
我不想再偷偷摸摸了
I'm really getting tired of sneaking around all the time.
我知道  我也是  不然我们  去外面度周末  就没人打扰我们
I know, me too. Hey, Y'know what if we went away for the whole weekend? Y'know we'd have no interruptions
还可以赤身裸体整个周末
And we could be naked the entire time.
整个周末  暴露个够
All weekend? That's a whole lot of naked.
我就说去开会  你就说去参加厨师研讨
Yeah, I could say I have a conference and you can say you have a chef thing.
我一直想参加泽西州的烹饪大会
Oh, I've always wanted to go to this culinary fair in Jersey!
不过  你去的不是那里
Ha, ha, okay. You know you're not, though.
对  好  走吧
Right. Okay. Let's go.
等等  乔伊怎么办
Wait. What about Joey?
老友记  第五季  第05集  谁进谁出
Friends  S05E05  The One With All the Kips
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
你们知道我这周末要干嘛吗
Hey, guess what I'm doing this weekend.
去纽泽西参加烹饪大会
Going to this culinary fair in Jersey.
真巧  钱德刚才说  要去那里开会
How weird! Chandler just told us he's got a conference there.
真有意思
Oh, that's funny
钱德应该  去康州或佛蒙特州开会
Seems like Chandler's conference could've been in Connecticut or Vermont.
我又不能决定在哪里开会
I'm not in charge of where the conference is held.
难道你希望大家认为我造假  我可没说谎
Do you want people to think it's a fake conference? It's a real conference.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
瑞秋在吗  我要找她
Is Rachel here? I gotta talk to her.
她出去逛街了
No, she's out shopping.
可恶  怎么了
Damn. What's going on?
我叫艾蜜莉来
I told Emily to come.
所以我得赶快跟瑞秋说
And I just need to, you know, talk to Rachel about it.
等等
Wait a minute.
艾蜜莉来了之后  你真的就不见瑞秋了
So when Emily comes, you're just, you're not gonna see Rachel anymore?
我现在只能专心想着 "我可以见我老婆"
Well look, I'm just trying to focus on the "I get to see my wife," part, all right?
不去想我快胄溃疡的事
And not the part that makes me do this.
所以你们  再也不能共处一室
Wow, so you guys are, you're never gonna be in the same room together?
这怎么可能
How is that even gonna work?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
但我一定会想到办法
But-but I assure you I will figure it out.
看起来实在不可能
It doesn't seem like it's gonna work.
大家好  嗨
Hi, guys. Hi.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
怎么了
What's going on?
我们正要帮摩妮卡翻床垫
We're flipping Monica's mattress.
我认为  应该先抬起来  再翻过来
So I'm thinking, basically, we pick it up, and then we flip it.
这方法比我的主意好
That's better than my way.
要不  你们顺便帮我翻好吗
Oh, hey, guys, would you flip mine too?
受不了
Oh, man.
我妈寄信来
Oh, look! A letter from my mom.
瑞秋
So, Rach?
你知道艾蜜莉要来
You know how Emily's coming, right?
我知道啊
Oh, yeah. I know.
听得到吗
Can you hear anything?
当然  刚刚有人说  "听得到吗"
Oh, yeah, somebody just said, "Can you hear anything?"
乔伊的大屁股
Hey, Joey's ass.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
记得上次他们吵架分手时  我们卡在房里没东西可吃吗
Well, remember when they got in that big fight and broke up and we were all stuck in her all night with no food or anything?
罗斯在婚礼上说出瑞秋名字后  我猜旧戏可能会重演
Well, when Ross said "Rachel" at the wedding, I figured it was gonna happen again.
所以我在这里藏了这些东西
You know? So I hid this in here.
有糖果  猜谜
Ooh, candy bars, crossword puzzles...
还有疯狂字谜   我要
Ooh, Mad Libs. Mine!
保险套
Condoms?
谁知道会在这里待多久
Hey, you don't know how long we're gonna be in here.
搞不好我们还得负责  繁衍人类后代
We may have to re-populate the Earth.
戴保险套还想繁衍后代
And condoms are the way to do that?
有个关键问题
Anyway, it all boils down to this.
上次我跟艾蜜莉通电话  天啊  我的狗死了
The last time I talked to Emily... Aah! Oh, my God! Our dog died!
什么  天啊  拉普死了
What? Oh, my God. LaPooh, our dog!
拉普还活着
LaPooh's still alive?
我妈说他被冰淇淋车撞倒
Oh! It says he was hit by an ice-cream truck
还被拖了19条街
and dragged for 19 blocks!
我的天啊
Oh! Oh, my God.
我们听到你在哭  别哭了
Sweetie, we heard you crying. Please don't cry.
是拉普
It's LaPooh!
我知道你觉得满肚子大便  过几天就没事了
I know, it's LaPooh right now but it'll get better.
不可思议  我们到了
I can't believe it! We're here!
枕头上还放巧克力  我最爱这套
Ooh, chocolates on the pillows! Oh, I love that!
那你应该跟乔伊住  到处都有巧克力糖
You should live with Joey. Roll-os everywhere.
我马上回来
Oh. Okay, be right back.
万岁
Oh, yes!
摩妮卡快来看  电视正在播警匪公路追逐战
Monica, get in here. It's a high-speed car chase on!
我们要换房间
We're switching rooms.
天啊  他们给了我们玻璃杯
Oh, dear God, they gave us glasses!
杯子上有口红印
They gave us glasses with lipstick on them.
如果连杯子都没换  谁知道还有哪些东西没换
If they didn't change the glasses, who knows what else they didn't change.
亲爱的  我只是希望  过个完美的周末
Oh, come on, sweetie. I just want this weekend to be perfect, okay?
换个房间  好嘛
We can change rooms, can't we? Okay.
好吧  要换就快换  5号直升机刚跟丢了
Okay, but let's do it now, though, because Chopper 5 just lost its feed!
（中央咖啡厅）
嘿
Hey, so, uh...
记得我上次有事想要告诉你吗
You know how there was something I wanted to talk to you about?
对
Oh, yeah.
嗯
Well...
你知道我很希望跟艾蜜莉合好
...you know I'm trying to work things out with Emily.
不过
Well, there's this...
有件事
...one thing.
好  我要说了
Okay, here goes.
我答应她了
I made a promise that
什么  你流鼻血
Oh hey! What? Your nose is bleeding.
天啊  你流血了
Oh, God! You're bleeding.
别又来了  我祖父去世时也一样
No! Oh not again! This happened when my grandfather died.
实在是抱歉
It's... Ugh, sorry.
好恶心
Oh, gross, unh.
好了  对不起  你刚才要说什么
Okay. So I'm sorry. What did you wanna tell me?
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
好
Okay.
我不能再见你了
I can't see you anymore.
我知道  真是的  我也看不见你
Yeah, I know, it's ridiculous. I can't see you, either.
我想你们可能会喜欢这间房
I think you'll find this room more to your liking.
太好了
Okay, great.
听说他只剩下一半的汽油了
They say he's only got half a tank left.
一半  那还可以跑很久
Half a tank? We still got a lot of high-speed chasing to do!
我们必须换房间  什么  为什么
We're switching rooms again. What? Why?
这间房是花园景观  我们订的是海景房
This is a garden-view room and we paid for an ocean-view room.
只剩一间海景房  可是你们不喜欢
Our last ocean-view room was unacceptable to you.
不好意思   我可以跟你谈一下吗
Excuse me. Um, can I talk to you over here for just a second?
钱德  来了
Chandler. Yeah?
这些小人想占我们便宜  我才没那么蠢
Look, these clowns are trying to take us for a ride. I won't let them.
我们可不是一对小孩
We're not a couple of suckers.
说得好  大姐头
I hear you, Mugsy.
这些房间都还好啊  请赶快选定  让我看
But, look, all these rooms are fine.Okay? Can you just pick one so I can watch the...
让我跟你一起好好度假
Have a perfect, magical weekend together with you?
我喜欢这间  没了
Okay, this one I like. Nothing.
没了  结束了
Nothing. It's over.
竟然没有延长时间
Damn it, this is regularly scheduled programming!
可以关掉电视吗
Can we turn the TV off, okay?
难道整个周末都要看电视
Do we really want to spend the entire weekend like this?
抱歉  我是不是  妨碍你换房间了
I'm sorry, am I getting in the way of all the room-switching fun?
你发火可别怪到我身上
Ha, ha, don't blame me for ruining tonight.
否则该怪谁  那个拖着行李  跑过10间房的倒霉服务生
Who should I blame? The nice bellman who had to drag our luggage to 10 rooms?
我不知道  或许该怪那个
I don't know, how about the idiot who thought he could drive...
以为用半箱汽油  就可以从纽约跑到加拿大的家伙
...from Albany to Canada on a half a tank of gas?
不要说死者的坏话
Do not speak ill of the dead.
我们出来就是为了过个浪漫的周末
We're supposed to be spending a romantic weekend together.
你到底哪里有毛病
it-it, What's the matter with you?
我只是想看点电视  有何不对
I just wanna watch a little television. What's the big deal?
放轻松嘛  老妈
Jeez, relax, Mom.
你说什么
What did you say?
我说 "放轻松  小摩"
I said, "Jeez, relax, Mon."
嗨
Hey.
瑞秋  我一直有话要告诉你
Hey. Rachel, I-I-I've been wanting to tell you something for a while now
我非说不可
and I really, I just have to get it out.
好  什么事
Okay. All right. What's up?
好
Okay.
你上次不是说我应该  不惜代价挽救婚姻吗
You know how you told me I should do whatever it takes to fix my marriage?
对  我叫你  答应艾蜜莉所有要求
Yeah, I told you to give Emily whatever she wants.
你的建议不错  不过我必须告诉你她要求
And while that was good advice, you should know that what she wants...
什么
Yeah?
就是叫我永远不能再见你
...is for me not to see you anymore.
太离谱了  你根本做不到
Well, that's crazy. You can't do that.
你怎么跟她解释
What are you gonna tell her?
天啊
Oh, my God.
你已经答应了  对不对
Oh, you've already agreed to this, haven't you?
我知道自己很糟糕
It's awful, I know. Uh, it's.
我心情也很糟糕  但这是挽救婚姻的唯一方法
I mean, I feel terrible, but I have to do this if I want my marriage to work.
我很希望跟她合好  必须挽救这段婚姻
And I do. I have to make this marriage work. I have to.
好在她来之前  我们还能继续见面
But the good thing is, we can still see each other until she gets here.
我真幸运
Oh, lucky me!
天啊  这真是好消息
Oh, my God! That is good news, Ross!
自从拉普过世之后  最大的好消息
I think that's the best news I've heard since LaPooh died!
你不知道我有多难过  我也很痛苦
You have no idea what a nightmare this has been. Uh, this is so hard.
是吗  真的吗  罗斯
Oh, yeah, really? Is it, Ross?
我可以为你减轻压力
Well, let me make this a little easier for you.
你做什么  愤而出走
What are you doing? Storming out.
瑞秋  这是你家
Rachel, this is your apartment.
你看我有多生气
Yeah? Well, that's how mad I am!
臭巧克力糖
Damn Rolos!
你回来了  嘿
Hey, you're back. Hey.
这次出差如何
How was your conference?
糟透了  我跟同事吵架  到回来前都没合好
It was terrible. I fought with my colleagues for the entire time.
怎么还有
Are you kidding with this?
那么  你整个周末都泡汤了
Uh, so your weekend was a total bust?
也不会  我看到  唐纳川普等电梯
Uh, no, I got to see Donald Trump waiting for an elevator.
嗨  你也回来了
Hi. Hey, you're back too.
对  钱德  可以出来一下吗
Yeah. Um, Chandler, could I talk to you outside for a second?
烹饪大会好玩吗  糟透了
How was your chef thing? Ugh. It was awful.
有些人根本不会欣赏美食
I guess some people don't appreciate really good food.
你的美食可能看起来很美味
Maybe it was the kind of food that tasted good at first...
吃下去却害人上吐下泻
...but then made everybody vomit and have diarrhea.
钱德  摩妮卡
Chandler. Monica.
旅馆费用多少  我要付我那一半
Okay, I'd like to know how much the room was because I'd like to pay my half.
很好  三百元
Okay, fine. $300.
三百元  就想成每间二十五元
Three hundred dollars? Yeah. Just think of it as $25 per room.
你们鬼叫什么
What are you guys woofing about?
钱德从我皮包偷了二十元纸钞
Chandler stole a 20 from my purse!
不会吧
No!
你看  我现在回头想想
You know what? Now that I think about it...
难怪我老是没有二十元的   原来你倒有很多
...I constantly find myself without 20s, and you always have lots.
你们应该看看她当时的表情
You should've seen the look on her face.
我不希望瑞秋恨我  真不知道该怎么办
I don't want Rachel to hate me. I don't know what to do.
你要听我的建议吗   请说
You want my advice? Yes. Please.
你听了一定不高兴  没关系
You're not gonna like it. That's okay.
你决定结婚太匆促了
You got married too fast.
这算哪门子忠告  看吧
That's not advice. I told you.
我去洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom.
要是有人叫我别见你们其中一个  我绝对办不到
Man, if anyone asked me to give up any of you, I don't think I could do it.
我也不行
Me neither.
或许我可以
Maybe I could do it.
嗨  嘿
Hi. Hey.
我知道你们听说  罗斯跟我的事情了
I know you guys heard about the whole thing with me and Ross.
我已经烦了一整天  请你们别再提起了
But I've been obsessing about it all day and would love not to talk about it.All right?
我不知道这算不算提起
Uh, I don't know if this falls under that category...
不过罗斯就在后面
...but, uh, Ross is right back there.
那才不是罗斯  不是那个
That's not Ross. Oh, no, not that guy.
虽然他很像
He does look like him, though.
罗斯去洗手间了
Okay. Ross is in the bathroom.
天啊  开始了  现在就这样
Oh, my God. It's happening. It's already started.
我就像阿吉
I'm Kip.
什么  你才不是阿吉
What? Yeah, you're not Kip.
你知道阿吉是谁吗
Do you even know who Kip is?
谁管他  你是瑞秋
Who cares? You're Rachel.
阿吉是谁
Who's Kip?
我以前的室友  以前也跟大家很好
Kip, my old roommate. We all hung out together.
那个可怜人
Oh, that poor bastard.
看吧  你们跟我说过那件事
See? You told me the story.
他以前跟摩妮卡约会  分手后却无法共处一室
He and Monica dated when they broke up they couldn't even be in the same room together
你们都答应继续跟他做朋友  结果呢
You all promised you'd stay his friend.And what happened?
还不是从此遭到排挤
He got phased out.
我们才不会排挤你
You're not gonna be phased out.
一定会  罗斯一定可以留下来  因为他是你哥哥
Well, of course I am.It won't happen to Ross. He's your brother,
他又是你大学室友
your old college roommate.
迟早有人会离开这个小圈子  我以前还以为走的是菲比
It was a matter of time before someone had to leave the group. I just always assumed Phoebe would be the one to go.
拜托  你住得远  又不是谁的亲戚
Honey, come on, you live far away, you're not related.
很快就会被淡忘
You lift right out.
嘿
Hey.
宾先生
Hey, Mr. Bing.
你住的饭店打电话来
That, uh, hotel you stayed at called.
说在你房间捡到睫毛夹
Said someone left an eyelash curler in your room.
是我的
Yes, that was mine.
我以为你钓上哪个马子  她忘了带走
I figured you hooked up with some girl and she left it there.
这种说法的确比较合理
Yes, that would have made more sense.
我都快要不认识你了
You know, I don't even feel like I know you anymore, man.
我只问你一次就好
All right, uh, look, I'm just gonna ask you this one time, all right?
无论你怎么说  我都相信你
And whatever you say, I'll believe you.
你是不是去参加同性恋大会
Were you or were you no on a gay cruise?
菲比
Phoebe.
我不该说大家都会淡忘你
I'm sorry about the whole lifting-out thing.
你得跟着我
You gotta come with me.
去哪里  跟着我就对了
Come where? Wherever I go.
你和我  我们可以重组一个团体  毕竟我跟你才是精华
Come on, you and me, we'll start a new group. We're the best ones.
好吧  不过记得拉乔伊入伙
Okay, but try to get Joey too.
菲比  我可以跟瑞秋私下谈谈吗
Pheebs, do you mind if I speak to Rachel alone for a sec?
当然可以
Oh, sure, yeah.
再见  罗斯
Bye, Ross.
永远不见了
Forever.
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
这不是违反规定吗
Isn't this against the rules?
我跟摩妮卡谈过
I talked to Monica.
是我做这个选择
Look, I'm the one who made the choice.
我害的大家必须要改变
I'm the one who's making things change.
所以离开的应该是我
So I should be the one to, you know, step back.
罗斯  真的没关系
Oh, Ross... No, no, it's okay. Really.
很多人只有在感恩节见到妹妹  同学会才见到大学室友
Plenty of people just see their sisters at Thanksgiving,and just see their college roommates at reunions
在 "汉堡王" 才见到乔伊
...and just see Joey at Burger King.
这样你舒服一点了吗
So is, is that better?
一点也没有
No, it's not better.
我还是见不到你
I still don't get to see you.
瑞秋  换做你会怎么办
Well, what would you do, Rach? If you were me, what would you do?
嗯
Well...
首先  我在婚礼上  不会说错名字
...for starters, I would have said the right name at my wedding.
竟然会是这样
I can't believe this is happening.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我也知道
I know that too.
瑞秋  抱歉打扰
Ahem. Hey, Rach? Sorry to interrupt
菲比说你要告诉我  谈谈旅行什么的
but, uh, Phoebe said you wanted to talk to me about a trip or something.
嘿
Hey. Hi.
嗨
Hi
我来
I just came over to drop off...
没事
...nothing.
上周末过得很糟吧
So that weekend kind of sucked, huh?
对  没错
Yeah, it did.
那大概我们完了
So I guess this is over?
什么  我说你跟我啊
What? Well, you know, you and me.
反正迟早得结束
I mean, it had to end sometime.
为什么
Why exactly?
因为上周末  我们吵架啊
Because of the weekend. We had a fight.
钱德  别傻了
Chandler, that's crazy.
如果你每次吵架就分手  交往大概不会超过...
If you give up every time you have a fight with someone,you'd never be with anyone longer than...
所以
So
我们还可以继续
this isn't over?
你真可爱
You are so cute!
当然  我们只是吵架
No, no. It was a fight.
吵过之后就算了
You deal with it and you move on.
根本没什么好害怕的
It's nothing to freak out about.
真的吗  太好了
Really? Okay, great.
欢迎加入成熟恋人行列
Welcome to an adult relationship.
我们还算是恋爱男女朋友
We're in a relationship?
恐怕是  好吧
I'm afraid so. Okay.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
摩妮卡  听说你上周  看到唐纳川普
Oh, hey, Monica, I heard you saw Donald Trump at your convention.
对  我看到他在等电梯
Yeah, saw him waiting for an elevator.
瑞秋  借我睫毛夹  我的丢了
Rach, can I borrow your eyelash curler? I think I lost mine.
好啊  在厕所
Yeah, it's in the bathroom.
乔伊  过来一下
Joey, can I talk to you for a second?
没错
Yes.
你  跟你
You? And you?
对  但是你不能告诉别人  还没有人知道
Yes, but you cannot tell anyone. No one knows.
怎么会  何时的事
But how? When?
要从伦敦说起  伦敦
It happened in London. In London!
我们之所以没告诉大家  是不想你们大惊小怪
The reason we didn't tell anyone was we didn't wanna make a big deal out of it.
这的确是大事
But it is a big deal!
我非告诉谁不可
I have to tell someone!
不行  你不能说
No, no, no. You can't.
拜托你  我们就是  不想面对大家质问
Please? Please?! We just don't want to deal with telling everyone, okay?
求求你  保证不说
Please, just promise you won't tell.
好吧
All right.
不可思议
Man, this is unbelievable!
这是件好事啊  可是
I mean, it's great! But...
我知道  的确很棒
I know. It's great!
我可不想看到这个
Oh, I don't wanna see that!
我们真是太蠢了
We're so stupid.
你知道他们在做什么吗
Do you know what's going on in there?
他们想抢走乔伊
They're trying to take Joey.
网球界最有名的菲比  就叫做杀球菲比
"The most popular Phoebe in tennis is called the overhand Phoebe. Heh.
赢了就得跟对方击掌  说 "嗨  菲比"
If you win, you must slap your opponent on the Phoebe and say, 'Hi, Phoebe!"'
真有意思  很好玩
Oh, that's cute. We really all enjoyed it.
但是这不算  不算什么
But you know it doesn't count. Count for what?
这可不算疯狂字谜
Just count in our heads as good Mad Libs.
我不想玩了  不好玩了
I guess fun time's over. Yeah, I'm done.
等等  要遵守规则才有意思  也才有意义啊
Wait, guys, if we follow the rules,it's still fun and it means something.
我要闪人了
I'm gonna take off.
有规则才好  不守规则怎么会好玩
Guys, rules are good!Rules help control the fun.